<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>MVSatish</title>
        <description>MVSatish - VenkataSatish Madala</description>
        <link>http://mvsatish.github.io</link>
        <link>http://mvsatish.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2013-06-23T00:35:31+05:30</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2013-06-23T00:35:31+05:30</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>For geeks - Live free or die</title>
                <description>&lt;h3 id='foss_philosophy'&gt;FOSS Philosophy:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOSS is a matter of the User&amp;#8217;s freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software. The “free” as is used in Free and Open Source Softwares refers to &amp;#8216;free as in freedom&amp;#8217; rather cost. More precisely it refers to four kinds of freedom to the user&amp;#8217;s of the Software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Freedom 0: The freedom to run the program for any purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Freedom 1: The freedom to study how the program works, and change it to make it do what you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Freedom 2: The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Freedom 3: The freedom to improve the program, and release your improvements (and modified versions in general) to the public, so that the whole community benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Idea being that once shared, the code will assist someone else – No need to Re-invent the Wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that, Knowledge is a Common Heritage of Mankind, and thus software, a form of knowledge, has to be free and accessible to all. And this en encumbers :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There must be “ Open Distribution” and “Open Modification”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All time Biggest Software Revolution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding is no longer the domain of just Software engineers. All branches of engineering use software tools, be it Computer Aided Design(CAD), Geographical Information Systems(GIS), Latex or Electronic Design Automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake up Engineers&amp;#8230;.. you are different from Ordinary Mortals (Isn&amp;#8217;t it?) Start Using Open Source Tools and Contribute to the world of real knowledge with Open Minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ An Open Document is much like a Physics Experiment to which hundreds of Researchers Contribute”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='internet_runs_on_foss'&gt;Internet Runs on FOSS:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you Know ? Internet Products like Wikipedia, Facebook, Drupal, Wordpress, Apache, Gmail, Firefox, Chrome etc purely rely on FOSS. Internet Runs on FOSS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that instance GOOGLE Inc is the largest FOSS Consumption Company. and It&amp;#8217;s Contribution to the Open Source is also Notable. More than 86% of Google Servers run on Linux based Servers. Google gives to Open Source Community through code.google.com and Google Summer of Code etc, If you look at Google, most of its products are free/ low cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many licenses are in use at FOSS Communities, among General Public License (GPL)(Most Linux Products like Ubuntu are GPL Compatible), BSD license(Google Uses most), CC-BY-SA License(Wikipedia Uses this), MIT license are Popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='__authored_by_mvsatish'&gt;# # Authored by MVSatish&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released Under CC-BY-SA License&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/12/29/forgeeksfoss</link>
                <guid>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/12/29/forgeeksfoss</guid>
                <pubDate>2011-12-29T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>HAM Radio -- Amateur Way</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you ever experienced No signal strength/Communication error using your Mobile/PDA ? Did you think of situation, when your mobile carrier&amp;#8217;s tower system crashed due to Cyclone,Earthquake or technical problem? During abnormal conditions, the only Communication you can rely to Help All Mankind is HAM Radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAM Radio is for anyone who likes to communicate with others via wireless technology, It is also for anyone who loves experimentation. Licensed Amateur Radio Operators Communicate with each other in nearby places, across the country, around the world or even with the astronauts in the outer space. Amateur Radio is a worldwide group of people who communicate with each other over a wide frequency spectrum using many different types of wireless transmitting modes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='heard_somewhere_about_spectrum_frequency'&gt;Heard somewhere about Spectrum, frequency??&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Wireless technology you can imagine has its own little frequency band: • Alarm Systems 40 MHz • Cell phones 824-849 MHz • Bluetooth 2.402 GHz – 2.480 GHz • Standard Cordless phones 40-50 MHz You might acquainted more with terms spectrum,frequency bands etc during 2G Scam and S-Band Spectrum Scam. OK, then what is Spectrum? Who Controls Spectrum allocations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spectrum is a limited natural resource and World Governments realizing the scarcity, cost and hence generating good revenue. In India, Wireless Planning and Coordination wing, Ministry of Communications is responsible for frequency spectrum management. It caters to F.M &amp;amp; A.M Radio bands, Mobile Carrier bands, TV Broadcasting, Broadband, Military and police needs and corporate deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corporates and FM Radio Companies investing lakhs and Crores to own their little band. For Example 98.3 MHz is a single frequency owned by Radio Mirchi to Broadcast Music for Commercial Purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know you are eligible to get various frequencies at free of cost!! Yes, in India certain frequencies are allotted to licensed HAM Operators aged above 12 yrs to operate their Amateur Stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Instance, VHF : 144-146 MHz UHF: 434-438 MHz and 1260-1300 MHz HF : 3500-3700 Khz, 3890-3900, 700-7100, 14000-14350 and lot more bands. Imagine, Thousands of frequencies in each band are allotted for HAM&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='what_types_of_people_you_can_meet_as_ham_'&gt;What types of people you can meet as HAM ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you walk down a street, you’ll pass men and women, girls and boys, and people of all ages, ethnic back grounds and physical abilities. They are Astronauts, Engineers, Doctors, Teachers, Students, Housewives, Politicians, Movie artist, Kings and workers like bankers, nurses, etc., Any of them might be a ham you will meet on radio whom, you never met but talk to them on the air. What other exciting things You can look forward to on HAM Bands? You might catch yourself excitedly calling a Russian cosmonaut in space or a sailor on the Coast Guard’s ship. You could be linked via packet radio with an US ham, a Parliamentarian or a king operating the Amateur Radio station aboard, or someone who is building the Transmitter &amp;amp; Receiver. On the other hand, a relaxing evening at home could find you in a friendly radio conversation with a ham in Kentucky or Frankfurt. Unlike any other activity, Amateur Radio knows no country boundaries and brings the world together as good friends. Although talking with astronauts isn’t exactly an everyday ham radio occurrence, more and more hams are doing just that, as many NASA astronauts are ham radio operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='hams_you_might_know'&gt;HAM&amp;#8217;s You might know:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As said earlier, HAM&amp;#8217;s come from all walks of life: Students, Teachers, Doctors, Engineers, Architects, Businessmen, Scientists, Film Stars, Kings and Prime Ministers making it a well knit international fraternity. Someprominent radio amateurs are late Prime Minister Sri Rajiv Gandhi(VU2RG), Smt.Sonia Gandhi(VU2SON), Mr. Amitabh Bachchan(VU2AMY), late King Hussein of Jordan(JY1), Actor Kamal Hasan(VU2HAS), late astronaut Kalpana Chawla(KD5ESI) and there are many more popular personalities&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='research_and_experimentations'&gt;Research and Experimentations:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you become HAM, you are permitted to experiment on Radio signals and Communications, wattage power, antennas, transceivers etcetera. You can collaborate with enthusiasts worldwide, who are working on same project. Another favourite activity hams enjoy is building their own radio equipment. Hams proudly stay at the forefront of technology, continually being challenged to keep up with advances that could be applied to the activity. Many have an incessant curiosity and eagerness to try new techniques. For a real challenge, you can try operating using low-power. Some enjoy operating with only 1 watt, or even less. It’s certainly a challenge, but with decent antennas and skillful operating, ham enthusiasts can be heard around the world. One of the best reasons for operating low power equipment is lightweight, inexpensive and easy to build. Some hams use nothing but “home-brew” equipment. In Technologically advanced countries like Japan and USA there are 1.2 million and 7.2 million HAM&amp;#8217;s respectively whereas in our Country the Count is below 16000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the number of licensee&amp;#8217;s increase in our country, the activity prevails and the way science and technology understood by students can be modified better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='license'&gt;License:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shortest path to Amateur Radio When you are ready, enthusiastic. We are here to guide you, train you and support you to become HAM. Vignan University-HAM Radio Club will take the Onus of educating more students towards the wonderful hobby -HAM Radio(In fact, HAM Radio is the recognized hobby of U.N.O ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='for_further_details_mail_your_queries_to'&gt;For further details: Mail your queries to&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vignanham@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://mvsatish.github.io/hobbies/2011/10/03/hamradio</link>
                <guid>http://mvsatish.github.io/hobbies/2011/10/03/hamradio</guid>
                <pubDate>2011-10-03T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Gibbery Words on my day</title>
                <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Thank You All for Your Heartily Wishes !!!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say, Today is Birthday! I got wishes by number of ways. Behest of vapid/ insensible and laze idiot in me, I sated the events from morning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking in&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. Few Phone Calls on my mobile that woke me up, of course in my late night deep sleep!!

2. Calls on My Land line

3. Lot Many SMS Wishes...

4. Some friends/relatives who walked in to my house, to wish me.

5. 2 Emails to both Gmail and Yahoo each.

6. Ultimate Wishes from Social Networks Facebook and Twitter.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want to Communicate with me on this Birthday through these Six Channels&amp;#8230; And Of course as always, many others who simply forgot my B&amp;#8217;day despite all these Channels :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what?? I&amp;#8217;m in the state of euphoria that I get wishes from the persons, I didn&amp;#8217;t even met in my life (Say Anonymous). And, My glee evaporates, when I notice that the Person, I love most doesn&amp;#8217;t wish me and often ask myself whether I deserve it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ponder at these two points and felt very interesting&amp;#8230; The Onus of picking the wishes is “mine” : For any reason, If I don&amp;#8217;t pick my wishes, I won&amp;#8217;t get it. What I Essentially mean is, I don&amp;#8217;t log on to facebook/Twitter for a week, I would get my wishes “late”. It is getting tougher to acknowledge wishes: For me it is boring to send back an SMS and or revert back in all these many Channels but after all, My Acknowledgement mean a lot to the Sender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one felicitous phrase, Technology is killing Us. By its impact, Personal is referred as &amp;#8216;Impersonal and Impersonal is backed as “Personal”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where would I be? Without Your Wishes Guys Once again, I would like to thank and appreciate your blessings/wishes for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall remember all your acquaintances. It is you people, made me to count a wonderful day!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/09/05/gibbery</link>
                <guid>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/09/05/gibbery</guid>
                <pubDate>2011-09-05T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Hazare Ji doing a Good thing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I consider applauding Anna Hazare at the very outset for having brought corruption to the National Centre stage. He encouraged a millions of anonymous indians to come out on the streets and get voice. I closely watched few students in my university thinking about the on-going fast and corruption than themselves much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anna exposed a political class, suffering from a grave moral crisis, to the wider world. He empowered those who’ve felt lost in a new India where wealth is the sole presiding deity. Anna become a symbol of change and hope at a time when a scam culture has assaulted the conscience of the nation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id='survivor_of_gandhian_ideology_'&gt;Survivor of Gandhian ideology? ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandhi, the greatest Indian , from whom Anna claim to derive inspiration, never went on a fast unto death by refusing medication. For Gandhi, the idea of fasting was a form of self purification, a fast could not be undertaken as he said, “out of anger. Anger is a short-term madness.” Yes, there is anger in the streets today, an almost volcanic eruption of a lava that has been simmering for decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some signs of unwanted situations in the last two months that are truly worrying. The gherao of the homes of members of Parliament may be visually appealing, but it encourages an anti-politician ‘sab neta chor hai’ rhetoric that could further destroy faith in parliamentary democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the British colonial rule, We chose parliamentary democracy to rule our country, our people. Accordingly, People elect representatives, they are responsible to make the laws but not an individual or a civil-groups. By any luck/unluck if this uncredited govt steps down to Jan-Lokpal bill , I&amp;#8217;m sure that will be credited as the result of Hazare&amp;#8217;s Fasting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where will this take us? How many fast-unto deaths we have to see? Most of, will start a fast-unto death to fulfill their demands! (Giving away seperate states, if hundred people sits down for fast-unto death??) There must be a procedure, I don&amp;#8217;t recommend a single person/group handling the laws over and above!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other way, Anna Team can agitate to get the government to commit to a special session of Parliament in six to eight weeks on an amended Lokpal Bill so that a new, well-considered law hails from Loksabha!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/08/24/annahazare</link>
                <guid>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/08/24/annahazare</guid>
                <pubDate>2011-08-24T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Indian It policy ever favours FOSS Growth?</title>
                <description>&lt;h3 id='the_open_source_trend_is_catching_on_in_the_it_and_electronics_space_in_india_with_enterprises_and_smes_taking_the_plunge'&gt;The Open Source Trend is catching on in the IT and Electronics Space in India, with Enterprises and SME&amp;#8217;s taking the plunge.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kerala Govt has been an early mover in utilising the advantages of Free and Open Source Software (FOSS) in all domains. Even,The enrollment for UID in Kerala was delayed because of the use of proprietary software by the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI), which has been resolved later. It’s a matter of pride that Kerala is the first State to implement Aadhaar using Free and Open Source Software (FOSS). The launch of Aadhaar is in complete compliance with the Kerala Government’s IT Policy of using FOSS in all aspects of governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, motivating success of Indian FOSS Community is Winning over the fight for Open Standards Policy For Building a Knowledgeable Society and encourage Tech savvy, Open Source is the essential component. The Government has to be involved at the adoption, appreciation and contribution level to help the Nascent Indian FOSS Community. It should also create a supportive environment through the right policies for FOSS companies to grow. Just the implementation of a policy that mandates the use of FOSS in large Govt Projects will spur the demand and Consumption of FOSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There Should be Technology Choice and avoidance of Vendor lock-in. It is reported that Computers of Dept of IT, AndhraPradesh(Various Other States also) were suffering from severe Virus-Attacks since long time. Why Govt&amp;#8217;s Should use huge amounts of public funds to pay royalties, license fee to Proprietary Software Vendors??? And Suffer from Virus attacks/ Restrict their own Freedom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various State Governments of India, Please Ponder at this Issue and extend your support to Open Source and Make India &amp;#8220;A Global FOSS Hub&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;National Knowledge Network Supports Open Source
Most of the Internet Products like Google, Wikipedia, Facebook supports and rely on FOSS
C-DAC is working for FOSS
Indian Operating System, BOSS is a Pure FOSS Product&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare IT Policies of Indian States:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assam IT Policy 2009 Kerala IT Policy 2007 AndhraPradesh IT Policy 2010-2015&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/06/28/fosspolicies</link>
                <guid>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2011/06/28/fosspolicies</guid>
                <pubDate>2011-06-28T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Eject Your CD-Rom Continously</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Geeks!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to Show you a Simple Program which Ejects your CD ROM Tray and Close it Continuously!!! And How to Compile a Program and Make it Executable!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='program_'&gt;Program :&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id='cd_rom_tray_eject__close_program'&gt;//Cd -Rom Tray Eject &amp;amp; Close Program&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id='program_written_by_satish'&gt;//Program Written by Satish&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id='licensed_under_gpl_free_to_use_share_and_modifydistribute'&gt;//Licensed Under GPL, Free to Use, Share and Modify/Distribute&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;//Program Start
main()
{
for(;;)
{
system(&amp;quot;eject&amp;quot;);
system(&amp;quot;eject-t&amp;quot;);
}
return 0;
}
//program end&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id='compilation_under_linux'&gt;Compilation Under Linux&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Text Editor &amp;amp; Copy the Above Program and Save it as simple.c&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Go to the Directory, where you saved the file simple.c using CD command&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Now Compile the program code is gcc simple.c -o simple&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Now You can Find the EXECUTABLE file in the Same Directory.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Double Click the EXE file and have fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a bientot, Au revoir!!! :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2010/12/29/ejectcd</link>
                <guid>http://mvsatish.github.io/articles/2010/12/29/ejectcd</guid>
                <pubDate>2010-12-29T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
